Elias Igbalajobi

Software developer in Lagos, Nigeria. • heeleeaz@gmail.com

Skilled mobile app developer and software engineer with over 9 years of experience. Work experiences include extended project with OperaPay and Osun State Ministry of Justice. Especially good at Java, Swift, Android, iOS and crafting full-stack solutions. Holds a B.Sc in Computer Science with Mathematics from Obafemi Awolowo University.

Portfolios	Experience	
Opera Software Android, iOS, Swift, Kotlin, Jira, GraphQL, Restful	HTML	9 years
Vela Solutions	CSS JavaScript	9 years 9 years
iOS, Swift, Restful, Spring boot Osun State Ministry of Justice	С	8 years
Android, AndroidSDK, Spring-Boot, MySQL, /Amazon S3, Amazon EC2, Amazon-Route 53, Amazon-SNS, Docker, Redis, SMS-Notification.	Java Android	8 years 6 years
The most amazing	iOS	3 years
Developed a library to determine at real-time, best Constant Rate Factor (CRF) for H.264 encoded videos based on Wifi-Tethering signal strength.	Swift Kotlin	3 years 1 years
Th.20- Cheded videos based on vviii Tealering signal salengal.	MacOS	6 months

Employment

Android/iOS Developer

Opera Software (OPay) • 2019 - Present

- Built an Android library (Pay-with-OPay) for merchants to integrate OperaPay system their application.
- Built OperaWealth(OWealth), an investment feature of the OperaPay application, which gives user 10% of their annual savings.
- Spent time fixing bugs in the Android app, from views to models to handling API calls. All issues were tracked in JIRA.
- Contributed as part of Android team in the development of OperaPay iOS application, worked on handling API calls to views and app deployment.

Technologies: Android, iOS, Swift, Kotlin, Jira, GraphQL, RxJava, RxSwift, CoreData, GoogleMap, Retrofit, GoogleMap, CocoaPod

iOS Developer

Vela Solution • 2018 - 2019

• Built Jaiz Bank iOS customer banking application

- Built Vela Bank iOS application, application work offline (without internet) using SMS service as a medium of data exchange.
- Built VCS(Vela control system) iOS library which allows third-party application to integrate basic banking services (Transfer and Bill payment) easily to their application.
- Built VCS(Vela control system) react native library interfacing the VCS iOS library for integration with react-native application.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Restful, CoreData, RxSwift, Spring boot

Android Developer Mentor

Andela Learning Community (ALC - 3.0) • 2018 - 2018

- Mentored and trained Android beginner level developers in Android basic.
- Involved in the selection of qualified ALC students for Udacity Android Nano degree course.

Technologies: Android, AndroidSDK, Udacity

Contract Android/Web Developer

Osun State Ministry of Justice • 2018 - 2018

- Developed an Android Application for 2018 state election and campaign process reporting.
- Developed a web-backend system using Spring-boot to store and process election process data.
- Developed an Admin Dashboard with real-time notification system to monitor all reported election processes.
- Setup and managed web infrastructure services.

Technologies: Android, AndroidSDK, Spring-Boot, MySQL, Amazon S3, Amazon EC2, Amazon-Route 53, Amazon-SNS, Docker, Redis, SMS-Notification.

Contract iOS Developer

Muve Logistics • 2018 - 2018

- Developed (Send-Me) iOS application for package delivery request and monitoring.
- Integrated an in-app purchase library.
- Added iPad layout.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, GoogleMap.

Android/iOS Developer

Independent • 2014 - Present

- Developed and published an audio/video streaming app (Copula for Android) from scratch. Copula makes it possible for a user to stream songs, videos and view images on nearby users devices without the use of internet.
- Developed a library to determine at real-time, best Constant Rate Factor (CRF) for H.264 encoded videos based on Wifi-Tethering signal strength, which was used in Copula App.
- Handle all of the coding and graphic design for Copula app as well. Sketch mockups are essential.
- Developed and published a video and image editing app(Storyart for Android). Storyart makes extensive use of FFMpeg and OpenGL library for creation, compression and manipulation of videos, and also image manipulation and transformation using various mathematical models respectively.
- Developed Android Emoji Keyboard library which was used in Storyart.
- Integrated with third-party APIs for account logins and enhanced functionality, including Facebook and Google.
- Developed a restful webservice system using Java JAX-RS, for maintaining a database of Storyart users information.
- Storyart has over 50,000 device installs and over 30,000 users. This project gave me first experience in building and maintaining a commercial quality app.

Technologies: Android, Android NDK, FFMpeg, OpenGL, Java, Jax-RS, Apache Cassandra, Redis, Amazon EC2, Restful.

View Storyart on Playstore • View Copula on Playstore

Contract Android Developer

Terrax Limited • 2013 - 2014

- Developed and published a personal banking (Cash transfer and bill payment) application (Veetu for Android)
- Integrated with third-party APIs for account logins and enhanced functionality, including Facebook and Google.

Technologies: Android, Restful, Facebook API

Experience

StoryartApp (Development)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.copula.storyart

Storyart is an image/video editing app I developed for Android. It allows image/video recording, image editing with filters, cropping etc, text editing with styling and animation, audio recording with trimming and effects. Sharing edited image or video to various social media(WhatsApp, Instagram and Facebook) as stories or post.

Copula (Development)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.copula.android

With Copula, you can stream songs, videos and view pictures on a nearby friend devices from your own

device without the use of internet. It works via Wifi-tethering with nearby device, permission must be granted by both parties before access.

Skills Languages

C, Swift, Java, Kotlin, C#, PHP, SQL, JavaScript, HTML

Libraries/APIs

OpenGL, NDK, FFmpeg, Core-Data, Realm, OkHTTP, iOS SDK, CocoaPods, JSON API, Facebook SDK, Facebook API. Google Map API.

Paradigms

App Development, Mobile Development, Functional Programming, Concurrent Programming

Platforms

MacOS, iOS, Android, Linux, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Storage

MySQL, Cassandra, Redis, Mamcached, SQLite

Education Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife • 2014 - 2019